pelican.com 2019-05-20

# Online Privacy Policy | Pelican

### INTRODUCTION

**Purpose**

We respect your privacy, and we are committed to protecting it through compliance with this policy. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to describe how Pelican Products, Inc. ("Pelican," “we,” “us,” or “our”) collects, uses, and shares information about you through our www.pelican.com and certain other Pelican owned websites identified below (collectively referred to herein as the "Site"). The Site and products offered for sale on and through the Site are intended only for residents of the United States and Canada.

This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect:

  * on our Site;
  * in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and our Site; and

It does not apply to information collected by:

  * us offline or through any other means, including on any other website operated by Pelican or any third-party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries); or
  * any third party (including our affiliates and subsidiaries), including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from the Site.

Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do. If you do not understand any aspects of our Privacy Policy, please feel free to Contact Us Online or as described at the end of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, you should not use our Site. By accessing or using this Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time (see Changes to Our Privacy Policy). Your continued use of this Site after we make changes to this Privacy Policy is deemed to be your acceptance of those changes, so please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates.

**Our Privacy Policy Explains**

Information We Collect and Why We Collect It

How We Use and Share Your Information

Access to Your Information and Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information

Security of Your Information

Consent to Processing of Personal Data in United States

Data Retention Periods

Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Complaints, Questions and How to Contact Us

**Scope; Third Party Websites**

This Privacy Policy applies only to information we collect at and through the Site, and certain Pelican affiliated websites accessible through or that may redirect you to our Site such as www.pelicanprogear.ca and www.pelicanprogear.com.au.

Some of our affiliated websites owned by Pelican such as www.peli.com, www.pelicanprogear.com are governed by their own separate privacy policies.

Our Site may also contain links to third party sites that are not owned or controlled by Pelican. For example, consumers in certain countries and jurisdictions may be directed to websites owned and operated by independent Pelican dealers.

Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of sites not owned or operated by Pelican.

Please review the privacy policy available on each site you visit for the privacy practices with respect to that website.

**Terms and Conditions**

Please note that your use of our Site and this Privacy Policy are subject to our Terms and Conditions.

### INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHY WE COLLECT IT

**Generally**

We collect several types of information from and about users of our Site (“Personal Data”), specifically information:

  * by which you may be personally identified, such as contact and login information, name, postal and work address, e-mail address, telephone number, payment information (e.g., bank account information, credit/debit card information, billing/shipping information), purchase information regarding products and services offered on our Site, opt-in selections for receiving additional information from Pelican, or other Personal Data you provide in connection with your use of the Site;
  * that is about you but individually does not identify you, such as traffic data, logs, referring/exit pages, date and time of your visit to our Site, error information, clickstream data, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Site; and,
  * about your internet connection, the equipment you use to access our Site and usage details.

By submitting a telephone number to us you agree that a representative of Pelican can contact you at the number you provide, potentially using automated technology (including texts/SMS messaging) or a pre-recorded message. Your consent is not an obligation to receive any of our products and/or services.

We collect this information:

  * directly from you when you provide it to us, for example when you submit orders or ask us questions;
  * automatically as you navigate through the Site. Information collected automatically may include usage details, IP addresses, and information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies; and,
  * From third parties, for example, Google Analytics, advertisers, service providers, ISPs and other business partners that allow us to better understand the use of our Site and how we can improve it.

**Information You Provide To Us**

You can provide information to us on our Site by filling in forms on our Site, such as when you create an account to use our Site, buy and order products from us, fill out our Contact Us form or create an account for dealer support. We also may keep records and copies of your correspondence (including email addresses) if you contact us. You may provide information to us through surveys, quizzes, and contests we administer. We also will collect information that you provide to us when you enter search queries. The information we collect includes Personal Data, such as your name, address, email address, payment account (e.g., bank, credit card, debit card) information, and telephone number. The Personal Data we collect from you is required to enter into a contract with Pelican, for Pelican to perform under the contract, and to provide you with our Site’s products and services. If you refuse to provide such Personal Data or withdraw your consent to our processing of Personal Data, then in some cases we may not be able to enter into the contract or fulfill our obligations to you under it.

You also may provide information to be published or displayed (hereinafter, “posted”) on public areas of the Site or transmitted to other users of the Site or third parties (collectively, “User Contributions”). Your User Contributions are posted on and transmitted to others at your own risk. Although we limit access to certain pages, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. Additionally, we cannot control the actions of other users of the Site with whom you may choose to share your User Contributions. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that your User Contributions will not be viewed by unauthorized persons.

**No Information From Children Under Age 18**

If you are under the age of 18, please do not attempt to register with us at this Site, purchase products or provide any Personal Data about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Data from a user under the age of 18, we will promptly delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from a user under the age of 18, please Contact Us Online or call us at (800) 473-5422. We are not liable for any damages that may result from a user’s misrepresentation of age.

**Information We Collect Automatically**

We collect certain information automatically as you use our Site, such as:

  * IP address
  * Browser type
  * Computer or device type
  * Unique device identifiers
  * Operating system version
  * The website from where you navigated to your Site
  * Time and date of using our Site
  * The name of your Internet service provider (ISP)
  * The pages anad products on our Site that you view and products selected
  * Location data

The information we collect automatically may include Personal Data, and we may maintain such automatically collected information or associate such automatically collected information with Personal Data we collect in other ways or receive from third parties. Such automatically collected information helps us to improve our Site and to deliver a better and more personalized service by enabling us to:

  * estimate our audience size and usage patterns;
  * store information about your preferences, allowing us to customize our Site according to your individual interests;
  * speed up your searches; and
  * recognize you when you return to our Site.

**Cookies**

Pelican and our service providers use cookies, web beacons, and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our Site through your computer or mobile device. When you visit the website again, the cookie allows that site to recognize your browser. Cookies may store unique identifiers, user preferences and other information. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some website features or services may not function properly without cookies. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including for storing user preferences, tracking user trends and providing relevant advertising to you (See Advertising, below).

We may also use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”) to gather and store aggregate information about visitors. Please use the following link to understand how Google Analytics collects and processes data: www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners. Google Analytics uses cookies (see the link for how) to help the website analyze how users use the Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (which may include your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google. We and the third parties we partner with currently do not process or comply with any web browser's "do not track" signal or other similar mechanism that indicates a request to disable online tracking of individual users who visit our websites or use our services. Some of our third party service providers may collect personal information on users of our Site over time and across different websites when users are visiting our Site.

### HOW WE USE AND SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

**To Provide Products, Services, and Information**

As described above, we collect information from you so that we can offer, sell and ship products to you and to provide you with information and support that you request from us. We use your information to register and service your online account, process orders for products, process payments, and fulfill your orders. We use your Personal Data to contact you about your orders and requests. We may send you information about our products and services, and new offerings. We may use your information to send newsletters, advertisements, or other promotional communications about our Site, products, and services. We may also administer surveys, sweepstakes, promotions, and contests using your information. We may provide information to third party service providers that help us maintain, fulfill, and deliver our Site and our products and services. We may use your information to notify you about changes to our Site or any products or services we offer or provide though them. In addition, we may use your information in any other way we may describe when you provide the information, for any purpose in which you provide it, and for any other purpose with your consent.

We may use third parties (including our subsidiaries and affiliates) to help host our Site; operate our online catalog, store and shopping experience; send out email updates about the Site; provide marketing and advertising services for us; remove repetitive information from our user lists; and provide and administer the Site, our products, and our services. These third party service providers will have access to your Personal Data in order to provide these services, but when this occurs we implement reasonable contractual and technical protections to limit their use of that information to helping us provide the service. We use demographic information to better understand our customers, and improve our products and services.

**Advertising**

We may use information we collect from you (through our Site or through third party service providers) about how you browse and shop in order to show you ads for Pelican’s products and services. We may use cookies and other information to provide relevant interest-based advertising to you. Interest-based ads are ads presented to you based on your browsing behavior in order to provide you with ads more tailored to your interests. These interest-based ads may be presented to you while you are browsing our site or third-party sites not owned by Pelican. If you wish to consent to such use, you can check the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your Personal Data or otherwise seek such consent. If you wish to change your choice, you may do so at any time by logging into the Site and adjusting your user preferences in your account profile by checking or unchecking the relevant boxes or by sending us an email stating your request to [communication@pelican.com](mailto:communication@pelican.com).

You can learn more about interest-based advertisements and your opt-out rights and options from members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) on its website (www.networkadvertising.org) and from members of the Digital Advertising Alliance on its website (www.aboutads.info). We do not control third parties’ collection or use of your information to serve interest-based advertising. However, these third parties may provide you with ways to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can also opt out of receiving targeted ads from members of the NAI on its website.

We belong to ad networks or use marketing companies that may use your browsing history across participating websites to show you interest-based advertisements on those websites. Please note that if you choose to opt out, you will continue to see ads on our Site, but they will not be based on how you browse and shop.

Our Site does not respond to “do not track” signals or similar mechanisms to indicate you do not wish us to collect information about your online activity or receive interest-based ads. To learn more about interest-based advertisements and your opt-out rights and options, visit the Digital Advertising Alliance and the Network Advertising Initiative websites (www.aboutads.info and www.networkadvertising.org).

**Your Consent**

In addition to sharing for reasons as described elsewhere in this Policy, we will share Personal Data with companies, organizations or individuals outside of the Pelican when we have your consent to do so.

**Legal Requests or Requirements and to Prevent Harm**

We will share Personal Data with third party companies, organizations or individuals outside of Pelican if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

  * Meet any applicable law, regulation, subpoena, legal process or enforceable governmental request.
  * Enforce applicable Terms and Conditions, including investigation of potential violations.
  * Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues.
  * Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Pelican, our users, customers or the public as required or permitted by law.

**Transfer in the Event of Sale or Change of Control**

If the ownership of all or substantially all of our business changes or we otherwise transfer assets relating to our business or the Site to a third party, such as by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy proceeding or otherwise, we may transfer or sell your Personal Data to the new owner. In such a case, unless permitted otherwise by applicable law, your information would remain subject to the promises made in the applicable privacy policy unless you agree differently.

### ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION AND CHOICES ABOUT HOW WE USE AND DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the Personal Data you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with control over your Personal Data:

  * **Reviewing Your Personal Data.** You can review and change your Personal Data by logging into the Site and visiting your “My Account” page. You may also notify us through the contact information below of any changes or errors in any Personal Data we have about you to ensure that it is complete, accurate, and as current as possible. Please note that if you request access to your Personal Data other than through our Site, you may be charged a fee subject to a maximum set by applicable law. We may also not be able to accommodate your request if we believe it would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.
  * **Tracking Technologies and Advertising.** You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe’s website. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
  * **Disclosure of Your Information for Third-Party Advertising**. We will only share your Personal Data with unaffiliated or non-agent third parties for promotional purposes with your express consent. If you wish to consent to such use, you can check the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your Personal Data or otherwise seek such consent. If you wish to change your choice, you may do so at any time by logging into the Site and adjusting your user preferences in your account profile by checking or unchecking the relevant boxes or by sending us an email stating your request to [communication@pelican.com](mailto:communication@pelican.com).
  * **Promotional Offers from Pelican.** We will only use your email address and other contact information to promote our own products and services with your express consent. If you wish to consent to such use, you can check the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your Personal Data or otherwise seek such consent. If you wish to change your choice, you may do so at any time by logging into the Site and adjusting your user preferences in your account profile by checking or unchecking the relevant boxes or by sending us an email stating your request to [communication@pelican.com](mailto:communication@pelican.com). If we have sent you a promotional email, you may send us a return email asking to be omitted from future email distributions. This opt out does not apply to information provided to the Pelican as a result of a product purchase, warranty registration, product service experience, or other transactions.

### SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION

In order to help protect your Personal Data, access to your data on our Site is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as a social security number) is protected by encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and our Site. To protect any data you store on our servers, we also regularly audit our system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and we use a tier-one secured-access data center. However, since the Internet is not a 100% secure environment, we cannot guarantee, ensure, or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. There is no guarantee that information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information. Please note that e-mails and other communications you send to us through our Site are not encrypted, and we strongly advise you not to communicate any confidential information through these means.

### CONSENT TO PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA UN UNITED STATES

This Site and products offered for sale are intended for residents of the United States and Canada, and are not intended for and are not directed to residents located outside of the United States or Canada. By using and accessing our Site, users who reside or are located in countries outside of the United States or Canada agree and consent to the transfer to and processing of Personal Data on servers located outside of the country where they reside, and that the protection of such information may be different than required under the laws of their residence or location. The data protection and other laws of the United States and Canada might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, but please be assured that we take steps to protect your privacy. By using our Site, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy.

### DATA RETENTION PERIOD

Pelican will retain your Personal Data for the entire time that you keep your account open. After you close your account, we may retain your Personal Data:

  * for as long as necessary to comply with any legal requirement;
  * on our backup and disaster recovery systems in accordance with our backup and disaster recovery policies and procedures;
  * for as long as necessary to protect our legal interests or otherwise pursue our legal rights and remedies; and,
  * for data that has been aggregated or otherwise rendered anonymous in such a manner that you are no longer identifiable, indefinitely.

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your consent in accordance with applicable law. We will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are material, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Privacy Policy changes). We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. The date this Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable email address for you, and for periodically visiting our Site and this Privacy Policy to check for any changes.

### COMPLAINTS, QUESTIONS, AND HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions, concerns, complaints or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy or otherwise need to contact us, please Contact Us or call us at (800) 473-5422. You may also contact us by mail at the following address:

  * Pelican Products, Inc.
  * 23215 Early Avenue
  * Torrance, California 90505
  * Tel: (310) 326-4700
  * Toll Free: (800) 473-5422
  * Fax: (310) 326-3311

If you are a resident of Canada, and you have a complaint about this Privacy Policy or our practices, you may make a complaint to the Privacy Commissioner of Canada. For more information, visit https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/report-a-concern/.
